<!-- Copyright (C) 2016 The Android Open Source Project

     Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
     you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
     You may obtain a copy of the License at

          http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

     Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
     distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
     WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
     See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
     limitations under the License.
-->
<resources>
    <!-- Title for the application. [CHAR LIMIT=12] -->
    <string name="app_name">Famous Women</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for family members [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_details">Details View</string>

    <!-- Category name for quiz [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_quiz">Quiz</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number one [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="maria">Maria Curie-Skłodowska</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number two [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="dalia">Dalia Grybauskaitė</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number three [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="elisabeta">Elisabeta Rizea</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number four [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="wanda">Wanda Rutkiewicz</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number five [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_five">five</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number six [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_six">six</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number seven [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_seven">seven</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number eight [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_eight">eight</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number nine [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_nine">nine</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary word for the number ten [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="number_ten">ten</string>

    <!--Details page subheader -->
    <string name="subheader_details_profession">Profession</string>
    <string name="body_details_description">Description</string>

    <!--Details page body -->
    <string name="body_details_description_dalia">Dalia Grybauskaitė (born in Vilnius on 1 March 1956), referred to as the \"Iron Lady\" or the
        \"Steel Magnolia\", is the President of Lithuania, inaugurated on 12 July 2009 and re-elected in May 2014. \nShe is the country\'s first
        female President and the first President of Lithuania to be reelected for a second consecutive term. \nIn her declaration speech for the 2009
        presidential election, Dalia Grybauskaitė said: \"I decided to return to Lithuania if the Lithuanian people decide I am needed there now.
        I think that we all long for the truth, transparency and responsibility for our country. We all want to live without fear, with confidence
        in ourselves, in each other, and in tomorrow. I can and I want to contribute with my experience, knowledge and skills to expel shadows from
        morality, politics, and economics to create a citizen-ruled Lithuania – a state of citizens. Therefore, I will run for the Lithuanian presidency.
        \" The international press was quick to dub her the \"Lithuanian Iron Lady\" for her outspoken speech and her black belt in karate.
        Dalia Grybauskaitė, who speaks Lithuanian, English, Russian, French and Polish, has mentioned Margaret Thatcher and Mahatma Gandhi as her
        political role models. \nShe was Vice-Minister of Finance (from 1999 to 2000), Vice-Minister of Foreign Affairs (from 2000-2001) and Minister
        of Finance (from 2001 to 2004). Lithuania joined the European Union on 1 May 2004, and Dalia Grybauskaitė was named a European Commissioner
        on the same day. She initially served as European Commissioner for Education, Culture, Multilingualism and Youth. She held this position
        until 11 November 2004, when she was named European Commissioner for Financial Programming and the Budget within the José Manuel Barroso-led
        Commission. In November 2005, she was elected Commissioner of the Year for her efforts to reform the EU budget. Dalia Grybauskaitė never had
        dreamt of becoming president, but rather pursued her career to the highest possible level, working hard at every opportunity.
        Her determination led her to run for presidency and seemed at the time to be the natural progression of her career. \nOn May 9, 2013
        President Dalia Grybauskaitė was presented the prestigious International Charlemagne Prize. The award, also known as \"Oscar in Politics\",
        has been extended to President Grybauskaitė for Lithuania\'s contribution to uniting the European Union and building the economic stability
        of the whole Europe. \"I dedicate the Charlemagne Prize, awarded by the people of Aachen, to the Lithuanian people. It signifies the
        recognition of our united efforts as we fought for Lithuania\'s freedom and its place in Europe as well as to overcome the economic crisis.
        This award is also a commitment to assume responsibility for bringing all the nations together to shape the future of Europe,\" the President
        emphasized at the award ceremony. \nDalia Grybauskaitė takes 68 place in Frobes The World\'s 100 Most Powerful Women list (2017 ranking).
        \nToday, Dalia is a modern leader and maintains a strong connection with the Lithuanian people through social media interaction,
        sharing her news, schedule and ideas.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_elisabeta">Elisabeta Rizea (28 June 1912 – 6 October 2003) was a Romanian anti-communist partisan in the
        Făgăraş Mountains of Northern Wallachia. After the Romanian Revolution, she became the symbol of Romania\'s anti-communism resistance.
        Rizea was born in Nucșoara, a small village in Argeş County in the Southern Carpathians, to a family of peasants who lived off plot of
        cultivated land. After World War II, as the Soviet Army imposed a Communist government in Romania, the peasants had to give up their
        land in order to implement collective farming. Out of opposition to this, Elisabeta Rizea and her husband joined an anti-Communist guerrilla
        group, Haiducii Muscelului, led by Colonel Gheorghe Arsenescu. Her assigned task within the group was to provide food and supplies.
        After she was captured by the Romanian militia in 1952, she was declared \"duşman al poporului\" (enemy of the people) and sentenced to
        death because she refused to give information about the other partisans. Eventually her sentence was commuted to seven years in prison.
        When Arsenescu was arrested in 1961, her sentence was extended by another 25 years, but three years later, in 1964, she was freed under
        the terms of a general amnesty.
        During her twelve years spent in prison, she was subjected to various forms of torture: she was hung by her hair from a hook and beaten
        until she fainted due to broken ribs, and was also scalped, burned, and beaten with a shovel. Upon her release from prison, she had no hair
        and she couldn\'t walk, as her knees had been destroyed by the torture.
    </string>

    <!--Missing String -->
    <string name="elisabeta_proffesion">Anti-Communist Partisant</string>

    <!-- Miwok translation for number one -->
    <string name="maria_profession">Physicist and chemist</string>

    <!-- Miwok translation for number two -->
    <string name="dalia_profession">President of Lithuania</string>

    <string name="wanda_profession">High mountain climber</string>

    <string name="humanitarian">Humanitarian</string>
    <string name="mother_theresa">Mother Theresa</string>
    <string name="body_details_description_mother_theresa">Mother Teresa (1910–1997) was a Roman Catholic nun who devoted her life to serving
    the poor and destitute around the world. Mother Teresa was born in 1910 in Skopje, the capital of the Republic of Macedonia.
    Little is known about her early life, but at a young age, she felt a calling to be a nun and serve through helping the poor.
    At the age of 18, she was given permission to join a group of nuns in Ireland. After a few months of training, with the Sisters of Loreto,
    she was then given permission to travel to India. She took her formal religious vows in 1931 and chose to be named after St Therese of Lisieux –
    the patron saint of missionaries.On her arrival in India, she began by working as a teacher; however, the widespread poverty of Calcutta
    made a deep impression on her, and this led to her starting a new order called “The Missionaries of Charity”. The primary objective
    of this mission was to look after people, who nobody else was prepared to look after.
    In 1948, she left the convent to live full-time among the poorest of Calcutta. She chose to wear a white Indian sari,
    with a blue border, out of respect for the traditional Indian dress. For many years, Mother Teresa and a small band of fellow nuns
    survived on minimal income and food, often having to beg for funds. But, slowly her efforts with the poorest were noted and appreciated
    by the local community and Indian politicians. In 1952, she opened her first home for the dying, which allowed people to die with dignity.
    The Missionaries of Charity now has branches throughout the world including branches in the developed world where they work with the homeless
    and people affected by AIDS. In 1965, the organisation became an International Religious Family by a decree of Pope Paul VI.
    In the 1960s, the life of Mother Teresa was brought to a wider public attention by Malcolm Muggeridge who wrote a book
    and produced a documentary called “Something Beautiful for God”.In 1979, she was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize “for work undertaken
    in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace.” She didn’t attend the ceremonial banquet
    but asked that the $192,000 fund be given to the poor. Over the last two decades of her life, Mother Teresa suffered various health problems,
    but nothing could dissuade her from fulfilling her mission of serving the poor and needy. Until her very last illness she was active
    in travelling around the world to the different branches of The Missionaries of Charity.
    Following Mother Teresa’s death, the Vatican began the process of beatification, which is the second step on the way to canonization and sainthood.
    Mother Teresa was formally beatified in October 2003 by Pope John Paul II.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_wanda">Wanda Rutkiewicz is one of the most recognizable high mountains female climber. She was the third woman and first European who reached Mount Everest  and the first woman ever on K2.
        \nWanda Rutkiewicz was born on 2 February, 1943 in Plungiany, Lithuania (before II World War it was part of Poland). She graduated from Wrocław University of Technology as electronic engineer. She was working in her profession in Wrocław, then she moved to Warsaw.
        \nWanda Rutkiewicz was always very active person: enough to mention volleyball, running,  shot put, the high jump, discus throwing and javelin throw. She had her first contact with climbing while she was on University in Wrocław. In 1965 she did climbing course in Tatra mountains. From the beginning she was adoring new activity. Two years after the course, in 1967, she started to climb in Alps. She became more and more experienced, her ambitions were also growing.
        She started to climb in Pamir, Hindu Kush and Himalayas.
        \nMain achievements:
        \n-	In 1967 east face of Aiguille du Grépon with Halina Krüger-Syrokomska – it was the first women only ascent.
    \n-	9-11 August, 1968 - East Pillar of Trollryggen in Norway with Halina Krüger-Syrokomska – it was the first women only ascent and seventh ever.
    \n-	1970 Lenin pick (7134 m) in Pamir, it was her first  seven-thousender.
    \n-	19-22 August 1973 the North Pillar of the Eiger (Messner route) in female team with Danuta Gellner-Wach i Stefania Egierszdorff.
    \n-	In 1975 she was leading women expedition on Gasherbrum. She climbed Gasherbrum III (7952 m) – women ascent altitude record. During the same expedition she climbed Gasherbrum II – first women-only ascent.
    \n•	On October 16, 1978 as the third woman and first European woman Wanda Rutkiewicz reached the top of Mount Everest, the Earth\'s highest mountain. That day Karol Wojtyła was chosen to become pope John Paul II. During his first pilgrimage to Poland he said to her \„Good God\'s will that same day we went so high\”.
    \n-	1978 –  the North Face of the Matterhorn in winter it was the first women-only-ascent with Anna Czerwińska, Irena Kęsa i Krystyna Palmowska.
    \n•	On July 15, 1985 with Krystyna Palmowska and Anna Czerwinska they climbed Nanga Parbat. They became the first women\'s expedition who reached this peak.
    \n•	On June 23 1986 she did the first women ascent on K2.
    \n•	With Ryszard Warecki she reached peak of  Shishapangma  (the true Main Summit) on September 18, 1978. They became first Polish on the top.
    \n•	On July 12, 1989 with Rhony Lampard they climbed Gasherbrum II.
    \n•	On July 16, 1990 with Ewa Panejko-Pankiewicz they reached Gasherbrum I (Hidden Peak).
    \n•	On September 1991, she reached solo Cho Oyu.
    \n•	On October 22, 1991, she climbed solo Annapurna.
    \nHer goal was to become the first woman to summit all fourteen of the eight-thousanders, finally she reached 8 of them (marked with •). The ninth one supposed to be Kangchenjunga. She climbed with Carlos Carsolio. On 12 May 1992 they started together from  camp IV. She was last seen when she was preparing bivouac while Carlos Carsolio was going down from the top after 12 hours ascent in deep snow. She didn’t have food, no bivouac equipment.
    It is not known if Wanda Rutkiewicz summitted Kangchenjunga, her body was not found. She probably died during night or next day, while ascending or maybe descending from the top.
    </string>




    <string name="about_application">About Application</string>
    <string name="quiz">Quiz</string>

    <!--Quiz Questions -->
    <string name="question1">Wanda Rutkiewicz was a famous...</string>
    <string name="answer1_1">Chemist</string>
    <string name="answer1_2">High mountain climber</string>
    <string name="answer1_3">Mathematician</string>

    <string name="question2">When did Mother Theresa receive her Noble Prize?</string>
    <string name="answer2_1">1959</string>
    <string name="answer2_2">1969</string>
    <string name="answer2_3">1979</string>

    <string name="question3">How many years did Elisabeta Rizea spend in prison?</string>
    <string name="answer3_1">02</string>
    <string name="answer3_2">12</string>
    <string name="answer3_3">22</string>
    

</resources>
