<!-- Copyright (C) 2016 The Android Open Source Project

     Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
     you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
     You may obtain a copy of the License at

          http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

     Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
     distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
     WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
     See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
     limitations under the License.
-->
<resources>
    <!-- Title for the application. [CHAR LIMIT=12] -->
    <string name="app_name">Famous Women</string>

    <!-- Category name for the famous woman description [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_details">Description</string>

    <!-- Category name for quiz [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_quiz">Quiz</string>

    <!-- Persons name in the famous woman list -->
    <string name="maria">Maria Skłodowska-Curie</string>
    <string name="dalia">Dalia Grybauskaitė</string>
    <string name="elisabeta">Elisabeta Rizea</string>
    <string name="mother_theresa">Mother Theresa</string>
    <string name="wanda">Wanda Rutkiewicz</string>
    <string name="ameenah">Ameenah Gurib-Fakim</string>
    <string name="maria_telkes">Mária Telkes</string>
    <string name="ellen_Sirleaf">Ellen Johnson Sirleaf</string>
    <string name="Merieme_Chadid">Merieme Chadid</string>
    <string name="ada">Ada E. Yonath</string>
    <string name="irena">Irena Sendler</string>
    <string name="ilhan">Ilhan Omar</string>
    <string name="valentina">Valentina Tereshkova</string>
    <string name="name10"> </string>

    <!--Persons proffesion -->
    <string name="elisabeta_proffesion">Anti-Communist Partisant</string>
    <string name="maria_profession">Physicist and chemist</string>
    <string name="dalia_profession">President of Lithuania</string>
    <string name="wanda_profession">High mountain climber</string>
    <string name="mother_theresa_profession">Humanitarian</string>
    <string name="ameenah_profession">President of Mauritius</string>
    <string name="maria_telkes_profession">Biophysicist</string>
    <string name="sirleaf_profession">President of Liberia</string>
    <string name="meriem_profession">Astronaut</string>
    <string name="ada_profession">Biochemist</string>
    <string name="irena_profession">Social Worker</string>
    <string name="ilhan_profession">Politician</string>
    <string name="valentina_profession">Cosmonaut</string>
    <string name="profession10"> </string>

    <!--Details page subheader -->
    <string name="subheader_details_profession">Profession</string>
    <string name="body_details_description">Description</string>

    <!--Details page body -->
    <string name="body_details_description_dalia">Dalia Grybauskaitė (born in Vilnius on 1 March 1956), referred to as the \"Iron Lady\" or the
        \"Steel Magnolia\", is the President of Lithuania, inaugurated on 12 July 2009 and re-elected in May 2014. \nShe is the country\'s first
        female President and the first President of Lithuania to be reelected for a second consecutive term. \nIn her declaration speech for the 2009
        presidential election, Dalia Grybauskaitė said: \"I decided to return to Lithuania if the Lithuanian people decide I am needed there now.
        I think that we all long for the truth, transparency and responsibility for our country. We all want to live without fear, with confidence
        in ourselves, in each other, and in tomorrow. I can and I want to contribute with my experience, knowledge and skills to expel shadows from
        morality, politics, and economics to create a citizen-ruled Lithuania – a state of citizens. Therefore, I will run for the Lithuanian presidency.
        \" The international press was quick to dub her the \"Lithuanian Iron Lady\" for her outspoken speech and her black belt in karate.
        Dalia Grybauskaitė, who speaks Lithuanian, English, Russian, French and Polish, has mentioned Margaret Thatcher and Mahatma Gandhi as her
        political role models. \nShe was Vice-Minister of Finance (from 1999 to 2000), Vice-Minister of Foreign Affairs (from 2000-2001) and Minister
        of Finance (from 2001 to 2004). Lithuania joined the European Union on 1 May 2004, and Dalia Grybauskaitė was named a European Commissioner
        on the same day. She initially served as European Commissioner for Education, Culture, Multilingualism and Youth. She held this position
        until 11 November 2004, when she was named European Commissioner for Financial Programming and the Budget within the José Manuel Barroso-led
        Commission. In November 2005, she was elected Commissioner of the Year for her efforts to reform the EU budget. Dalia Grybauskaitė never had
        dreamt of becoming president, but rather pursued her career to the highest possible level, working hard at every opportunity.
        Her determination led her to run for presidency and seemed at the time to be the natural progression of her career. \nOn May 9, 2013
        President Dalia Grybauskaitė was presented the prestigious International Charlemagne Prize. The award, also known as \"Oscar in Politics\",
        has been extended to President Grybauskaitė for Lithuania\'s contribution to uniting the European Union and building the economic stability
        of the whole Europe. \"I dedicate the Charlemagne Prize, awarded by the people of Aachen, to the Lithuanian people. It signifies the
        recognition of our united efforts as we fought for Lithuania\'s freedom and its place in Europe as well as to overcome the economic crisis.
        This award is also a commitment to assume responsibility for bringing all the nations together to shape the future of Europe,\" the President
        emphasized at the award ceremony. \nDalia Grybauskaitė takes 68 place in Frobes The World\'s 100 Most Powerful Women list (2017 ranking).
        \nToday, Dalia is a modern leader and maintains a strong connection with the Lithuanian people through social media interaction,
        sharing her news, schedule and ideas.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_elisabeta">Elisabeta Rizea (28 June 1912 – 6 October 2003) was a Romanian anti-communist partisan in the
        Făgăraş Mountains of Northern Wallachia. After the Romanian Revolution, she became the symbol of Romania\'s anti-communism resistance.
        Rizea was born in Nucșoara, a small village in Argeş County in the Southern Carpathians, to a family of peasants who lived off plot of
        cultivated land. After World War II, as the Soviet Army imposed a Communist government in Romania, the peasants had to give up their
        land in order to implement collective farming. Out of opposition to this, Elisabeta Rizea and her husband joined an anti-Communist guerrilla
        group, Haiducii Muscelului, led by Colonel Gheorghe Arsenescu. Her assigned task within the group was to provide food and supplies.
        After she was captured by the Romanian militia in 1952, she was declared \"duşman al poporului\" (enemy of the people) and sentenced to
        death because she refused to give information about the other partisans. Eventually her sentence was commuted to seven years in prison.
        When Arsenescu was arrested in 1961, her sentence was extended by another 25 years, but three years later, in 1964, she was freed under
        the terms of a general amnesty.
        During her twelve years spent in prison, she was subjected to various forms of torture: she was hung by her hair from a hook and beaten
        until she fainted due to broken ribs, and was also scalped, burned, and beaten with a shovel. Upon her release from prison, she had no hair
        and she couldn\'t walk, as her knees had been destroyed by the torture.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_mother_theresa">Mother Teresa (1910–1997) was a Roman Catholic nun who devoted her life to serving
    the poor and destitute around the world. Mother Teresa was born in 1910 in Skopje, the capital of the Republic of Macedonia.
    Little is known about her early life, but at a young age, she felt a calling to be a nun and serve through helping the poor.
    At the age of 18, she was given permission to join a group of nuns in Ireland. After a few months of training, with the Sisters of Loreto,
    she was then given permission to travel to India. She took her formal religious vows in 1931 and chose to be named after St Therese of Lisieux –
    the patron saint of missionaries.On her arrival in India, she began by working as a teacher; however, the widespread poverty of Calcutta
    made a deep impression on her, and this led to her starting a new order called “The Missionaries of Charity”. The primary objective
    of this mission was to look after people, who nobody else was prepared to look after.
    In 1948, she left the convent to live full-time among the poorest of Calcutta. She chose to wear a white Indian sari,
    with a blue border, out of respect for the traditional Indian dress. For many years, Mother Teresa and a small band of fellow nuns
    survived on minimal income and food, often having to beg for funds. But, slowly her efforts with the poorest were noted and appreciated
    by the local community and Indian politicians. In 1952, she opened her first home for the dying, which allowed people to die with dignity.
    The Missionaries of Charity now has branches throughout the world including branches in the developed world where they work with the homeless
    and people affected by AIDS. In 1965, the organisation became an International Religious Family by a decree of Pope Paul VI.
    In the 1960s, the life of Mother Teresa was brought to a wider public attention by Malcolm Muggeridge who wrote a book
    and produced a documentary called “Something Beautiful for God”.In 1979, she was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize “for work undertaken
    in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace.” She didn’t attend the ceremonial banquet
    but asked that the $192,000 fund be given to the poor. Over the last two decades of her life, Mother Teresa suffered various health problems,
    but nothing could dissuade her from fulfilling her mission of serving the poor and needy. Until her very last illness she was active
    in travelling around the world to the different branches of The Missionaries of Charity.
    Following Mother Teresa’s death, the Vatican began the process of beatification, which is the second step on the way to canonization and sainthood.
    Mother Teresa was formally beatified in October 2003 by Pope John Paul II.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_wanda">Wanda Rutkiewicz is one of the most recognizable high mountains female climber. She was the third woman and first European who reached Mount Everest  and the first woman ever on K2.
        \nWanda Rutkiewicz was born on 2 February, 1943 in Plungiany, Lithuania (before II World War it was part of Poland). She graduated from Wrocław University of Technology as electronic engineer. She was working in her profession in Wrocław, then she moved to Warsaw.
        \nWanda Rutkiewicz was always very active person: enough to mention volleyball, running,  shot put, the high jump, discus throwing and javelin throw. She had her first contact with climbing while she was on University in Wrocław. In 1965 she did climbing course in Tatra mountains. From the beginning she was adoring new activity. Two years after the course, in 1967, she started to climb in Alps. She became more and more experienced, her ambitions were also growing.
        She started to climb in Pamir, Hindu Kush and Himalayas.
        \nMain achievements:
        \n-	In 1967 east face of Aiguille du Grépon with Halina Krüger-Syrokomska – it was the first women only ascent.
        \n-	9-11 August, 1968 - East Pillar of Trollryggen in Norway with Halina Krüger-Syrokomska – it was the first women only ascent and seventh ever.
        \n-	1970 Lenin pick (7134 m) in Pamir, it was her first  seven-thousender.
        \n-	19-22 August 1973 the North Pillar of the Eiger (Messner route) in female team with Danuta Gellner-Wach i Stefania Egierszdorff.
        \n-	In 1975 she was leading women expedition on Gasherbrum. She climbed Gasherbrum III (7952 m) – women ascent altitude record. During the same expedition she climbed Gasherbrum II – first women-only ascent.
        \n•	On October 16, 1978 as the third woman and first European woman Wanda Rutkiewicz reached the top of Mount Everest, the Earth\'s highest mountain. That day Karol Wojtyła was chosen to become pope John Paul II. During his first pilgrimage to Poland he said to her \„Good God\'s will that same day we went so high\”.
        \n-	1978 –  the North Face of the Matterhorn in winter it was the first women-only-ascent with Anna Czerwińska, Irena Kęsa i Krystyna Palmowska.
        \n•	On July 15, 1985 with Krystyna Palmowska and Anna Czerwinska they climbed Nanga Parbat. They became the first women\'s expedition who reached this peak.
        \n•	On June 23 1986 she did the first women ascent on K2.
        \n•	With Ryszard Warecki she reached peak of  Shishapangma  (the true Main Summit) on September 18, 1978. They became first Polish on the top.
        \n•	On July 12, 1989 with Rhony Lampard they climbed Gasherbrum II.
        \n•	On July 16, 1990 with Ewa Panejko-Pankiewicz they reached Gasherbrum I (Hidden Peak).
        \n•	On September 1991, she reached solo Cho Oyu.
        \n•	On October 22, 1991, she climbed solo Annapurna.
        \nHer goal was to become the first woman to summit all fourteen of the eight-thousanders, finally she reached 8 of them (marked with •). The ninth one supposed to be Kangchenjunga. She climbed with Carlos Carsolio. On 12 May 1992 they started together from  camp IV. She was last seen when she was preparing bivouac while Carlos Carsolio was going down from the top after 12 hours ascent in deep snow. She didn’t have food, no bivouac equipment.
        It is not known if Wanda Rutkiewicz summitted Kangchenjunga, her body was not found. She probably died during night or next day, while ascending or maybe descending from the top.
    </string>

    <string name="body_details_description_ameenah">Born 17 October 1959 is a Mauritian biodiversity scientist and politician serving as President of Mauritius since 2015. In December 2014, she was selected to be the presidential candidate of the Alliance Lepep. After Kailash Purryag resigned on 29 May 2015, both Prime Minister Sir Anerood Jugnauth and Leader of the Opposition Paul Berenger positively welcomed her nomination,
        which was unanimously approved in a vote in the National Assembly. Gurib-Fakim is the first woman elected President of the country and is the third woman to serve as Head of State. She worked as Managing Director of CIDP Research and Innovation (formerly Cephyr, Centre for Phytotherapy Research), where she devoted her time to researching the medical and nutritive implications of indigenous plants of Mauritius.
        Previously, she was a Professor with a personal chair in Organic Chemistry at the University of Mauritius (2001) and where she served successively as Dean of the Faculty of Science and Pro–Vice Chancellor (2004–2010). She also worked at the Mauritius Research Council as Manager for Research (1995–1997). She served as the Chairperson the International Council for Scientific Union – Regional Office for Africa (2011–2014).
        Gurib-Fakim has also been the recipient of various international awards including the L\'Oréal-UNESCO Award for Women in Science (2007), Laureate for the National Economic and Social Council (2007), the CTA / NEPAD / AGRA / RUFORUM for \‘African Women in Science\’ and the African Union Award for Women in Science.She was also made Commander of the Order of the Star and Key of the Indian Ocean (CSK)
        by President Anerood Jugnauth in 2008 for her contribution in the education and the scientific sector. She was awarded the Order of the \‘Chevalier de l\’Ordre des Palmes Academiques\’ by the Government of France in 2009. Upon becoming President, she was automatically elevated to the highest civilian award of Grand Commander of the Star and Key of the Indian Ocean (GSCK).
        </string>

    <string name="body_details_description_maria_telkes">Mária Telkes (December 12, 1900 – December 2, 1995) was a Hungarian-American scientist and inventor who worked on solar energy technologies.\nTelkes worked as a biophysicist in the United States; and, from 1939 to 1953, she was involved in solar energy research at Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
        \nTelkes is known for creating the first thermoelectric power generator in 1947, designing the first solar heating system for the Dover Sun House in Dover, Massachusetts, (built entirely with solar heating, with the architect Eleanor Raymond and the first thermoelectric refrigerator in 1953 using the principles of semiconductor thermoelectricity.
        \nShe was a prolific inventor of practical thermal devices, including a miniature desalination unit for use on lifeboats, which used solar power and condensation to collect potable solar still. The still saved the lives of airmen and sailors who would have been without water when abandoned at sea.
        \nOne of her specialties were phase-change materials, including molten salts to store thermal energy. One of her materials of choice was Glauber\'s salt.elkes is considered one of the founders of solar thermal storage systems, earning her the nickname "the Sun Queen".
        \nShe moved to Texas in the 1970s and consulted with a variety of start-up solar companies, including Northrup Solar, which subsequently became ARCO Solar, and eventually BP Solar.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_sirleaf"> Liberian President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf is the world\'s first elected black female president and Africa\'s first elected female head of state.
        Ellen Johnson Sirleaf was born on October 29, 1938, in Monrovia, Liberia. A graduate of the College of West Africa at Monrovia, she went on to receive her bachelor\'s degree in accounting from the Madison Business College in Madison, Wisconsin, a degree in economics from the University of Colorado at Boulder and a Master of Public Administration degree from Harvard University.
        After returning to Liberia, Ellen Johnson Sirleaf served as assistant minister of Finance in President William Tolbert\'s administration. In 1980, Tolbert was overthrown and killed by army sergeant Samuel Doe, who represented the Krahn ethnic group. Johnson Sirleaf went into exile in Nairobi, Kenya, as well as in the United States, where she worked as an executive in the international banking community.
        In 1985, Johnson Sirleaf returned to Liberia and ran for a seat in the Senate, but when she spoke out against Doe\'s military regime, she was sentenced to 10 years in prison. She served a partial sentence before moving to Washington, D.C. When she returned to her native country for a third time in 1997, it was as an economist, working for the World Bank and Citibank in Africa.
        After supporting Charles Taylor\'s bloody rebellion against President Samuel Doe in 1990, Johnson Sirleaf ran unsuccessfully against Taylor in the 1997 presidential election. Taylor subsequently charged Johnson Sirleaf with treason. In 2005, after campaigning for the removal of President Taylor, Johnson Sirleaf took over as leader of the Unity Party.
        That year, promising economic development and an end to corruption and civil war, she was elected to the Liberian presidency. When she was inaugurated in 2006, Johnson Sirleaf, or the \"Iron Lady\", as she was also known, became the world\'s first elected black female president and Africa\'s first elected female head of state.
        Ellen Johnson Sirleaf has four sons and six grandchildren, some of whom live in Atlanta, Georgia. </string>


  
    <string name="body_details_description_meriem"> In March 2005, astronomer and explorer Merieme Chadid became the first Moroccan woman to set
        foot on Antarctica, where she planted the flag of Morocco – the first Arab flag to be placed in this remote location. Listed by Forbes
        Magazine as one of the thirty most interesting workers in the world,
        Chedid was one of the astronomers involved in installing VLT telescopes in Chile\'s barren Atacama Desert, and is considered to be the
        world\'s first astronomer to be committed to installing the large astronomical observatory in Antarctica, where she has carried out
        pioneering work at Dome C of the Concordia Research Station.
        Born in Casablanca on 11 October 1969, Merieme Chadid became interested in astronomy from a young age. A book about 17th century German
        astronomer and mathematician Johannes Kepler further inspired her, as did a radio broadcast by fellow Moroccan and astronomy enthusiast
        Albert Pilot. She contacted Pilot regarding her interest
        in the field and he encouraged her to pursue her passion for astronomy, which she continues to do.
        After earning an MA in physics at the University of Casablanca, Chadid moved to Nice where she studied imaging science, before continuing
        her education at the Observatoire de Haute-Provence, obtaining a PhD for her study entitled Stellar Pulsation and Evolution. Her career
        continued as an engineer astrophysicist at
        the National Center for Scientific Research located in Montpellier, France. It was while working in this capacity that Merieme Chadid was
        selected by the European Southern Observatory to work on the installation of the VLT – Very Large Telescope – in the Atacama Desert.
        Of all her many achievements, Merieme notes that one of her most treasured accomplishments has been her work at Dome C in Antarctica,
        describing it as one of the coldest, most deserted and inaccessible places in the world, and comparing the installation of an observatory
        there as resembling a space mission.
        With night continuing for several months of the year, researchers at the station have the advantage of being able to study the stars 24/7
        if they need to. Certainly, this Moroccan astronomer has come a long way since she first studied the night skies in the country of her
        birth. </string>

    <string name="body_details_description_ada">
        Ada Yonath (born 22 June 1939) is an Israeli crystallographer best known for her pioneering work on the structure of the ribosome.
        In 2009, she received the Nobel Prize in Chemistry along with Venkatraman Ramakrishnan and Thomas A. Steitz for her studies on the
        structure and function of the ribosome, becoming the first Israeli woman to win the Nobel Prize out of ten Israeli Nobel laureates,
        the first woman from the Middle East to win a Nobel Prize in the science, and the first woman in 45 years to win the Nobel Prize
        for Chemistry.
        \nHowever, she said herself that there was nothing special about a woman winning the Prize.
    </string>

    <string name="body_details_description_irena">Irena Sendler was a 29-year-old social worker, employed by the Warsaw Welfare Department, when
        World War II broke out. She took advantage of her job in order to help the Jews, by offering them food and shelter.
    \nIn November 1940, when the Warsaw Ghetto was sealed off, it became practically impossible to help isolated Jews. The Ghetto was a small area
    with 400,000 Jewish people forced into it. The poor hygienic conditions in the crowded ghetto, the lack of food and medical supplies resulted
    in epidemics and high death rates. Sendler managed to obtain a permit from the municipality that enabled her to enter the ghetto to inspect
    the sanitary conditions. Assisted by a group of co-workers, she devised means to help the Jews.
    \nThis work was done at huge risk, as giving any kind of assistance to Jews in German-occupied Poland was punishable by death.
    \nWith the help of Council for Aid to Jews (Żegota), Sendler smuggled approximately 2,500 Jewish children out of the Warsaw Ghetto and then
    provided them with false identity documents and helped set up hiding places for them (Polish Christian families or orphanages). Irena and
    others who went with her into the ghetto, used different methods to smuggle children out: in ambulances and trams (hiding them in packages
    and suitcases), by secret underground passages, and many other ways.
    \nSendler was determined to prevent the children from losing their Jewish identities, she made sure that each person hiding a child realised
    the child must be returned to Jewish relatives after the war, she also kept careful documentation listing the children\'s fake Christian names,
    their given names, and their current location.
    \nThe German occupiers eventually discovered her activities, and she was arrested in 1943. She was tortured during the questioning - she had
    her legs and feet fractured. Despite this, she refused to betray any of her comrades or the children they rescued, and was sentenced to death.
    Żegota saved her life by bribing the guards on the way to her execution. After her escape, she hid from the Germans, but returned to Warsaw
    under a fake name and continued her involvement with the Żegota until the end of the war.
    \nAfter the war, she and her co-workers gathered all of the children\'s records with the names and locations of the hidden Jewish children and
    gave them to their Żegota colleague and his staff at the Central Committee of Polish Jews.
    \nAlmost all of the children\'s parents had been killed at the Treblinka extermination camp or had gone missing.
    \n\nIn 1965, Sendler was recognised by Yad Vashem as one of the Righteous among the Nations. Late in life, she was awarded the Order of the
    White Eagle, Poland\'s highest honour, for her wartime humanitarian efforts. She was nominated for the Nobel Peace Price twice.
    \nWith the exception of diplomats who issued visas to help Jews flee Nazi-occupied Europe, Sendler saved more Jews than any other individual
    during the Holocaust.</string>

    <string name="body_details_descriprion_maria_sklodowska">Was a Polish and naturalized-French physicist and chemist who conducted pioneering
        research on radioactivity. She was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize, the first person and only woman to win twice, the only person to win
        a Nobel Prize in two different sciences, and was part of the Curie family legacy of five Nobel Prizes. She was also the first woman to become a
        professor at the University of Paris, and in 1995 became the first woman to be entombed on her own merits in the Panthéon in Paris.
        She was born in Warsaw, in what was then the Kingdom of Poland, part of the Russian Empire. She studied at Warsaw\'s clandestine Flying University
        and began her practical scientific training in Warsaw. In 1891, aged 24, she followed her older sister Bronisława to study in Paris, where she
        earned her higher degrees and conducted her subsequent scientific work. She shared the 1903 Nobel Prize in Physics with her husband Pierre Curie
        and with physicist Henri Becquerel. She won the 1911 Nobel Prize in Chemistry.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_ilhan">
        Ilhan Omar was born 1982 in Mogadishu and was raised in Baydhabo, Somalia. In 2016, she was elected a Democratic–Farmer–Labour Party member of
        the Minnesota House of Representatives, making her the first Somali-American Muslim legislator elected to office in the United States. She is
        the Director of Policy and Initiatives of the Women Organizing Women Network.
        She was the youngest of seven siblings, and grew up in an upper-middle-class household. Ilhan\'s father, Nur Omar Mohamed, is Somali, and worked
        as a teacher trainer.
        Her mother was Yemeni, and died when she was a child. She was thereafter raised by her father and grandfather. Ilhan\'s grandfather, Abukar, was
        the director of Somalia\'s National Marine Transport, with her uncles and aunts also working as civil servants and educators. After the start of
        the civil war in 1991, she and her family fled the country and spent four years in a refugee camp in Kenya.
        In 1995, Omar and her family immigrated to the United States, initially settling in Arlington, Virginia. In 1995, they moved to Minneapolis, where
        Ilhan quickly learned English in only three months.
        Her father and grandfather inculcated in her the importance of democracy. She also began to accompany her grandfather to caucus meetings at the
        age of 14 years, serving as his interpreter.
        Omar attended Edison High School, and volunteered there as a student organizer. After high school, she attended North Dakota State University,
        where she participated in the Muslim Student Association.
        She graduated with bachelor\'s degrees in political science and international studies.</string>

    <string name="body_details_description_valentina">
        Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova was born in the Yaroslavl Region of Russia on March 6, 1937. She was the second born of three children.
        Her father was a tractor driver and her mother worked in a textile plant. Valentina began school in 1945 at the age of eight.
        In 1953, she left school and began working. She continued her education by correspondence courses.
        \nValentina became interested in parachute jumping at an early age. It was her expertise in parachute jumping that led to her selection as a cosmonaut.
        Tereshkova was a textile-factory assembly worker and an amateur parachutist when she was recruited into the cosmonaut program.
        Under the direction of Soviet premier Nikita Khrushchev, four women were selected to be trained for a special woman-in-space program.
        Of the four women selected, only Valentina Tereshkova completed a space mission.
        \nTereshkova was launched aboard Vostok 6 on June 16, 1963 and became the first woman to fly in space.
        During the 70.8 hour flight, Vostok 6 made 48 orbits of Earth.
        Upon completion of her mission, Tereshkova was honored with the title Hero of the Soviet Union.
        She never flew again, but she did become a spokesperson for the Soviet Union.
        While fulfilling this role, she received the United Nations Gold Medal of Peace.
        \nOn November 3, 1963, Tereshkova married astronaut Andrian Nikolayev.
        Their first child, a daughter named Elena, was a subject of medical interest because she was the first child born to parents who had both been exposed to space.
        Elena later went on to become a medical doctor. Tereshkova and Nikolayev divorced in 1980.
    </string>


    <!--Menu Options -->

    <string name="about_application">About Application</string>
    <string name="quiz">Quiz</string>

    <!--Quiz Questions -->

    <string name="quizResult">Your result is: \u0000</string>
    <string name="quizCorrect">Number of correct answers: \u0000</string>
    <string name="quizIncorrect">Number of wrong answers: \u0000</string>


    <!--Question 1 -->
    <string name="question1">Wanda Rutkiewicz was a famous...</string>
    <string name="answer1_1">Chemist</string>
    <string name="answer1_2">High mountain climber</string>
    <string name="answer1_3">Mathematician</string>

    <!--Question 2 -->
    <string name="question2">When did Mother Theresa receive her Noble Prize?</string>
    <string name="answer2_1">1959</string>
    <string name="answer2_2">1969</string>
    <string name="answer2_3">1979</string>

    <!--Question 3 -->
    <string name="question3">How many years did Elisabeta Rizea spend in prison?</string>
    <string name="answer3_1">2 years</string>
    <string name="answer3_2">12 years</string>
    <string name="answer3_3">22 years</string>

    <!--Question 4 -->
    <string name="question4">What is Dalia Grybauskaitė famous for?</string>
    <string name="answer4_1">She is President of the Republic of Lithuania</string>
    <string name="answer4_2">She is President of the Republic of Latvia</string>
    <string name="answer4_3">She is President of the Republic of Estonia</string>

    <!--Question 5 -->
    <string name="question5">How is Dalia Grybauskaitė referred to?</string>
    <string name="answer5_1">Black Swan and Big bird</string>
    <string name="answer5_2">Lithuanian Iron Lady and Steel Magnolia</string>
    <string name="answer5_3">Iron Magnolia and Steel Lady</string>

    <!--Question 6 -->
    <string name="question6">Elisabeta Rizea was a ....</string>
    <string name="answer6_1">Romanian anti-communist partisan</string>
    <string name="answer6_2">Romanian communist partisan</string>
    <string name="answer6_3">Albanian anti-communist partisan</string>

    <!--Question 7 -->
    <string name="question7">What did Mária Telkes design 1940\'s?</string>
    <string name="answer7_1">First biomass heating system in a house</string>
    <string name="answer7_2">First solar heating system in a house</string>
    <string name="answer7_3">First electric heating system in a house</string>

    <!--Question 8-->
    <string name="question8">What was Mária Telkes nickname?</string>
    <string name="answer8_1">The Water Queen</string>
    <string name="answer8_2">The Wind Queen</string>
    <string name="answer8_3">The Sun Queen</string>

    <!--Question 9-->
    <string name="question9">In 1997, Ellen Johnson Sirleaf worked as an economist in which bank?</string>
    <string name="answer9_1">Global Bank Liberia.</string>
    <string name="answer9_2">International Bank (Liberia)</string>
    <string name="answer9_3">World Bank and Citibank in Africa</string>

    <!--Question 10-->
    <string name="question10">Which Nobel Prize was Ada Yonath awarded?</string>
    <string name="answer10_1">Nobel Prize in Chemistry</string>
    <string name="answer10_2">Nobel Prize in Literature</string>
    <string name="answer10_3">Nobel Prize in Physics</string>

    <!--Question 11-->
    <string name="question11">How many Jewish children saved Irena Sendler?</string>
    <string name="answer11_1">17</string>
    <string name="answer11_2">about 400</string>
    <string name="answer11_3">about 2,500</string>

    <!--Question 12-->
    <string name="question12">Irena Sendler:</string>
    <string name="answer12_1">founded Polish Underground State during II World War</string>
    <string name="answer12_2">is one of the Righteous among the Nations</string>
    <string name="answer12_3">received the Nobel Prize in Literature</string>

    <!--Question 13-->
    <string name="question13">When Ilhan Omar was elected?</string>
    <string name="answer13_1">1991</string>
    <string name="answer13_2">2016</string>
    <string name="answer13_3">2013</string>

    <!--Question 14-->
    <string name="question14">How many turns around the Earth Valentina Tereshkova made on the Vostok 6?</string>
    <string name="answer14_1">16</string>
    <string name="answer14_2">48</string>
    <string name="answer14_3">63</string>
    <string name="search_hint">Name of Women</string>


</resources>
